Dr. David Ashley White Papers, 1965-2001
University of Houston Libraries
Dr. David Ashley White Papers
1965-2001
White, David Ashley
Dr. David Ashley White is currently the Director of the Moores School of Music at the University of Houston, where he is also professor of composition and theory. This collection consists of published and manuscript scores, programs, correspondence, audio-visual materials, and other items relating to his career as both a composer and music instructor.
40 boxes; 18 linear feet
1992-001
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Acquisition
Donated by Dr. David Ashley White, 1991-present.
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Index Terms
Subjects
Choral Music; Chamber Music; Composition (Music); Hymns; Hymn Writers; Music -- Manuscripts; University of Houston Curricula; University of Houston Faculty
Subjects (Persons)
White, David Ashley; Kennan, Kent Wheeler, 1913-; Tomatz, David, 1935-
Subjects (Organizations)
University of Houston; University of Houston. Office of the President.; Moores School of Music
Formats
Scores; Correspondence; Programs; Sound recordings
Biographical Note
Dr. David Ashley White is currently the Director of the Moores School of Music at the University of Houston, where he is also professor of composition and theory. He was born on December 11, 1944 in San Antonio, Texas. Dr. White began his musical education at Del Mar College in Corpus Christi, Texas earning an Associate of Arts in 1966. He then transferred to the University of Houston in 1966 to pursue an undergraduate degree in oboe performance, which he earned in 1970; he finished a Master's degree in Composition at the University of Houston in 1974. He went on to the University of Texas at Austin and received his Doctor of Musical Arts in Composition in 1978. Dr. White has taught at the University of Houston since 1975, first as lecturer and then as instructor. He became Assistant Professor in 1978 and Associate Professor in 1983; he has been a full Professor since 1990. Dr. White was appointed Director in 1999.
David Ashley White's secular and sacred compositions are widely performed and published. Sources for his frequent commissions include Piccolo Spoleto, the Texas Chamber Orchestra, the Mirecourt Trio, the Green Lake Festival, the Concert Chorale of Houston, Del Mar College, the University of Houston, the Houston Harpsichord Society, Houston Masterworks Chorus, the Houston Chamber Choir, and a number of churches and individuals. Since 1980 he has received the ASCAP Award for music composition.
White is currently resident composer for the Houston Chapter of the American Guild of Organists (AGO). In 1991 and 1995 he was composer-in-residence at the Mississippi conference on Music and Liturgy, as he was in July 1998 at the Evergreen Church Music Conference in Colorado. White was winner of the 1993 composition contest sponsored by St. Paul United Church of Christ, Chicago ( Cantata Domino for mixed voices, brass, and organ, published by Paraclete Press). He has also won first prizes from the Episcopal diocese of Alabama, the Virginia Bandmasters Association, and the Texas Federation of Music Clubs.
David Ashley White is a prolific composer whose secular publishers are E.C. Schirmer, Southern Music Company and Shawnee Press, and his sacred music publishers include Selah, Paraclete, St. James, Abingdon, Trinitas, Hinshaw, and MorningStar. His hymns are found in a number of books, including The Hymnal 1982 (Episcopal), the recently published supplement to that book, Wonder, Love, and Praise, The United Methodist Hymnal, Japan's Hymnal for the United Church of Christ, and Great Britains' Worship Songs Ancient and Modern. A collection of his hymns, Sing My Soul: David Ashley White Hymnal, was published in 1996 by Selah Publishing Co.
Scope and Contents
The Dr. David Ashley White Papers consist of forty boxes of materials dating from 1965 to 2001 with the bulk of the collection dating from 1980-1998. The first donation to this collection occurred in 1991, which was processed in 1993. Dr. White has made numerous additions since then and future material is expected. This collection consists of published and manuscript scores, programs, correspondence, audio-visual materials, and other items relating to his career as both a composer and music instructor. The collection has been divided into six series: Scores and Manuscripts, Programs, Correspondence, Professional Activities, Personal Materials and Audio/Visual Materials.
Detailed Description
- Scores and Manuscripts, 1965-2001 (Box 1-20)
  The Scores and Manuscripts series dates from 1965-2001, with the bulk of the series dating from 1980-1998. This is the largest series in the collection with nineteen boxes containing hundreds, of Dr. White's original pencil/ink manuscripts. The series has been arranged into eight sub-series based on the type of musical composition: Choral Music, Chamber Music, This Bitterly Beautiful Land, Larger Orchestral Works, Solo Voice with piano and/or Other Instruments, Solo Instruments, Hymn Tunes, and Miscellaneous. Published pieces have been included when available.
  - Choral Music, 1967-2001 (Box 1-11)
    There are 181 folders in this sub-series, which have been arranged alphabetically by title. This is the strongest area of the collection containing most of the sacred and secular vocal compositions.
    - Above Love's Door, June 24, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alleluia, June 1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alleluia, Song of Gladness, October 20, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alleluia! The Paschal Moonlight Almost Past, May 9, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - All Things Bright and Beautiful, February 8, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Amazing Grace, December 27, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - And His Gifts, March 13, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - And I Heard the Voice of the Lord, June 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Apple Tree, September 27, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Arise, My Love, September 27, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - As Panting Deer, December 14, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - As the Father Has Loved Me, July 10, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Away In a Manger, April 17, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Behold, He Came!, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Behold Now, Bless the Lord, February 27, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Blessed May Thou Be, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - The Blue Estuaries, June 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bread of Heaven, March 16, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bright the Cloud and Bright the Glory, March 21-24, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - The Call, October 27, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Cantate Domino, October 24, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Celebrations and Reflections, August 17, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Christians, We Have Met to Worship, June 19, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Christ Song, July 8, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Come Away to the Skies, October 12, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Come Down, O Love Divine, January 6, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Come, Holy Spirit, Heavenly Dove, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Come Holy Spirit, Revive Your Church, December 11, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Come Home Again, October 10, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Come, Pure Hearts, June 5, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Come, Pure Hearts: Spiritual Songs From the Frontier, June 5, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Come, Thou Fount of Every Blessing, January 23, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Come, Thou Long Expected Jesus, August 26, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Come, Ye Sinners, November 30, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Comfort, Comfort Ye My People, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Consecration, April 15, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Creator of the Stars of Night, July 8, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - The Day of Resurrection!, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Earth Has Many a Noble City, August 26, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - The Earth is the Lord's, October 6, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - An Easter Alleluia, March 11, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - The Easter Canticle, February 20, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Easter Fanfare, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Easter - Wings, October 12, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Elegy and Exaltation, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Erinnyes, August 18, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Evening Service, August 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Evening Star, March 4, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - The Eyes of All, January 30, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - A Fanfare and Dance for Spoleto, May 7, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Fanfare for a Festive Occasion, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - A Festival Triptych, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Filled with the Spirits Power, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - For the Beauty of the Earth, July 14, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - For the Means of Grace and for the Hope of Glory, February 1, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Four Elizabethan Images, May 23, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Four Impressions, April 22, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - From the Womb, January 22, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Frontier Songs, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - God and Love Are One, December 12, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - God So Loved The World, June 2, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - God The Spirit, April 9, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - The Great Commission, April 25, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Great is the Lord, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Hail, King of the Angels, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Hear My Cry, Holy One, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Hilariter, January 1, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Hope Is the Harrowing, May 2, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - How Many Wonders, June 11, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - How Shallow Former Shadows Seem, June 27-30, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - I Believe in God, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - I Belong to God, June 22, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - I Sought The Lord, June 19, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - I Will Arise, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - In Christ There Is No East or West, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - In Dark Clouds Hidden, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Infant Holy, Infant Lowly, December 25, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Is a Murmuring Dove Nearby, July 9-10, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - It Came Upon The Midnight Clear, June 10, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - It Is Well With My Soul, June 21, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Into A New Unity, May 7, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Into the Woods My Master Went, May 16, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Journey to the Interior, April 9, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Jubilate, July 1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - The Kingdom of Love, May 11, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - King of Glory, King of Peace, October 11, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - A Lenten Prayer, July 12, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Like the Murmur of the Dove's Song, October 11, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Lord, Have Mercy Upon Us, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - The Lord is King, December 22, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Lord, Make Us Instruments, August 10, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - The Lord My Shepherd, December 19, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Lord's Prayer, for St. Paul's Pieces and Responses, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Love Came Down at Christmas, October 20, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - The Love of Christ, October 19, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Magnificat and Nunc Dimittis, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - The Maiden's Song, October 24, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Mass For A Celebration, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Miserere Mei, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Most High, Omnipotent, Good Lord, July 26, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Music For Evensong, September 30, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - My Shepherd Will Supply My Need, August 1, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - No More a Stranger or a Guest, November 2, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - O Bread of Life from Heaven, June 1, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - O Breath of Life, December 31, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - O God of Love, August 1, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - O God of Mercy, July 11, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - O God, Unseen, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - O Heavenly Word, Eternal Light, May 23, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - O Jesus, I Have Promised, October 3, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - O Light of Light, May 28, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - O Love Divine, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - O Love of God, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Our Help Comes From the Lord, June 13, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Our Holy Tribute, This, June 22, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - O Word, That Goest Forth On High, November 3, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - The Pelican, October 7, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - People of Faith, July 2, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Phos Hilaron, March 9, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Praise, My Soul, the King of Heaven, June 2, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - The Praising Word, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Preces and Responses, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Promised Land, January 21, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Psalm 23, July 25, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Psalm 30, May 12, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Psalm 51, Have Mercy On Me, O God, February 2, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Psalm 67, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Psalm 70, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Psalm 103, June 9, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Regent Square, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - The Reign of Peace, October 15, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Rejoice, Ye Pure in Heart, February 22, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Remembrances, April 10, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Renew Me, O Eternal Light, May 2, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Responses for the Church Year, 1978-1983 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Ring the Broken Pail, October 30, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Sanctus, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Savior, Like A Shepherd Lead Us, June 3, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Service Music, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Set Me As A Seal, January 27, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - A Setting of the Eucharist: Rite One, Book of Common Prayer (BCP), May 27, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - The Silence of a Stone, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Sing Aloud, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Sing Praise to the Lord, August 10-11, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - A Solemn Prayer, August 17, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - A Song to Sing, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - A Song to the Lamb, August 16, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Son of the Father, December 25, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - So the Day Dawn for Me, June 28, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - The Spirit of the Lord, March 4, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Star in the East, December 7, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Stir Up Your Power, November 6, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Surely It Is God Who Saves Me, June 7, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Sweet Infancy! O Heavenly Fire, April 20, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Take My Life, April 15, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - There's A Wideness In God's Mercy, April 22, 1992/1993 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - The Things, Good Lord, May 18, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - This Glimpse of Glory, June 1, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - This Is A Day of New Beginnings, May 10, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Three Carols for the Nativity, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Three Wise Men, September 11, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Tide of Angels, March 31, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - True Anointed One, December 16, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Two Canticles, April 19, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Two Christmas Images, May 28, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Two Fragments From the Song of Solomon, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Two Psalm Settings: 67 and 70, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - The Upward Call, September 8, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Vertue, September 28, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Vespers, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - We the Lord's People, May 12, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - What Star Is This?, September 15, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - When In Our Music, July 7, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - When Jesus Died To Save Us, October 3, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - When Lilacs Lasted In The Dooryard Bloomed undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - When, Lord To This Our Western Land, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Wherefore, O Maker, March 22, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Without The Fire, There Is No Burning, March 25, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - With The Body That Was Broken, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - You Are The Way, March 19, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Zechariah's Song, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Chamber Music, 1965-1998 (Box 11-12)
    There are twenty-two folders in this sub-series, which have been arranged alphabetically by title. This sub-series includes the manuscript for Lament, the earliest musical piece by Dr. White in this collection. The requisite instrumentation is given for each piece.
    - Air and Burlesque for oboe or violin, bassoon or cello, and piano, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Ariosa (Reflections on an Original Tune), 1986 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Canzona for oboe and harpsichord, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Divertimento for violin and viola, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Dreams within Dreams for flute and percussion, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Elegy and Exaltation for violin, cello, and piano, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Elegy for oboe and piano, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - The Elm Is Scattering for oboe and piano, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - The Elm Is Scattering for violin, cello, and piano, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Erinnyes for flute, violin, bassoon and piano, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Lament for cello and piano, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - L'isola di S. Michele Nocturne for oboe and piano, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Overtune: A Man's A Man, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Peasant Dances, Lullaby, Waltz, Song, March Suite for 10 pianos, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Psalm 88 for oboe and organ, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Quartet for strings, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Sonata for clarinet and piano, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Suite for violin and piano, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Tempest Music, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Triptych: Prelude, Capriccio, and Hymn for brass quintet and organ, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Version of Ward for oboe, violin and cello, January 1995 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - This Bitterly Beautiful Land, 1986 (Box 12-14)
    This sub-series contains a cantata commissioned by the Concert Chorale of Houston as part of the Texas Sesquicentennial Celebration in 1986. A research grant in the spring of 1985 facilitated the composing of this work. This sub-series includes background materials and notes, individual movements, instrumental parts, and both incomplete and complete scores.
    - David Ashley White Explanatory Notes, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Background, David Ashley White Family History, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Texts Considered or Used, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Text Permissions, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Prologue, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - A Letter From Texas, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - I Hear..., 1986 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - A Good Horse, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Mister Maverick, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - El Dorado, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - El Dorado page of pencil manuscript when Zubin [Mehta] died, January 1, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - To Know the Cowboy and the Desert, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - By What Lost Campfire, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Los Inditos and Pray for the Ranger, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - I Will Arise and Go to Jesus, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Oh, My Lovin' Brothuh, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - One's Feeling, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Take Away, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Finale, March 2, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Incomplete Working Score, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Incomplete Working Score, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Print Master of Score, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Final Score Unbound, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Final Score Bound, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Instrumental Parts, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Program Notes, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Larger Orchestral Works, 1966-1998 (Box 14-15)
    There are six folders in this sub-series, which have been arranged alphabetically by title. Aside from This Bitterly Beautiful Land, these are the most elaborate of Dr. White's compositions.
    - Concertino for trumpet and string orchestra, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - The Elm Is Scattering for oboe and orchestra, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Homages, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Hymn To Aten, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - The Ruins of Missolonghi for small orchestra, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Songs of Immortality I, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Solo Voice with piano and/or Other Instruments, 1972-2000 (Box 15-16)
    There are nine folders in this sub-series, which have been arranged alphabetically by title. The voice type and instrumentation are given with each piece.
    - Gathering the Lost Garden for mezzo-soprano, clarinets (b-flats and bass) and piano, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Lamentations for soprano, cello and piano, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Long Live Fair Eleana for soprano and piano, May 23, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Of Sunday Natures for mezzo-soprano, oboe, autoharp and antique cymbal, October 5, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - The Peace of Wild Things songs for soprano and piano, 1973,1979 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Songs from Queen's Road for soprano, clarinet, and piano, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Songs from Queen's Road for soprano, flute, and piano, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Three Byron Songs for baritone and piano, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Three Elizabethan Images for high voice/piano, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Solo Instruments, 1969-1999 (Box 16-17)
    There are nine folders in this sub-series. Solo Instruments included are flute, organ, and piano. The pieces have been arranged first by instrument and then alphabetically.
    - Flashbacks for solo flutes, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Aria Organ Solo, November 2, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Brewer's Trumpet for organ solo, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Night Cries for organ, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Reflections On a Tune organ solo, June 1986 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Five Glimpses for piano, 1972,1983 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Four Brief Pieces for piano, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Phantasy and Toccata for piano, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Songs for Lorca for piano, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Hymn Tunes, 1970-2000 (Box 18-20)
    There are 115 folders in this sub-series, which have been arranged alphabetically by title. David Ashley White is considered by many to be one of the most prolific hymn composers of modern times. Many of these hymns have been selected for publication by Selah Publishers. The researcher may also wish to look at the Correspondence Series for additional information on Selah Publishers. Published hymns have been included with their appropriate title. Proofs for Dr. White's Hymnary are included at the end of this sub-series.
    - Alan, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - All Souls; Biltmore, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Alphege, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Anglican Chant, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Ashley, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Austin, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Azzolina, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Beach Spring, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Bennett, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Bering Memorial, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Bishop Powell, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Bonelli, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Bonhoeffer, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Bradford, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Breneman, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Brewer, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Christ Church Cathedral, undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Christopher, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Clinton, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Cumberland, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Daniel, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 21)